<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Portfolio</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Communicating with R and Python</title>
      <link>/blog/communicating/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/communicating/</guid>
      <description>In my computational biology class, we’ve been learning how to use both R code and Python in R studio. Now, I’m a total novice at coding and so when I first saw this I was like “Why? Why do I need to do this?”. And then it finally clicked.
My parents immigrated here in the the early 1990s and have been here since. However in order to live in Texas, they’ve learned a decent amount of English (and a little bit of Spanish).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2</title>
      <link>/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project2/</guid>
      <description>#Introduction I chose the cancer dataset from the survival package. This dataset contains information pertaining to the survival of lung cancer patients from the North Central Cancer Treatmnet Group. Originally, I chose 6 variables from the dataset. However, I had to mutate certain variables in order to get binary and categorical variables. I also had to change the levels of the binary variable from “1” and “2” to “0” and “1” for later use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 1</title>
      <link>/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project1/</guid>
      <description>##Introduction
I chose the topic of movies for my project because I’m an avid movie watcher. I tend to go see most if not all blockbuster hits in theatres as soon as they’re released. If I’m not at the movies, I also have the habit of rewatching films I like over and over at home.
The dataset ‘imdb’ contains information from the IMDb website about a certain selection of movies released between the years 2006-2016.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Projects Here are some projects I have recently completed:
  Exploratory Data Analysis with Tidyverse Tools
  Modeling, Testing, and Classification
  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>